<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Brain Kosmos RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[My personal blog - writing about tech, hobbies, and topics I'm interested in to keep me sane.]]></description><link>https://blog.rickychon.me</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 03:12:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello there! This is my first blog post. I’m not exactly sure how I will use this blog or how to write posts, but hopefully I will publish…]]></description><link>https://blog.rickychon.me/2022/01-04-hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.rickychon.me/2022/01-04-hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! This is my first blog post. I’m not exactly sure how I will use this blog or how to write posts, but hopefully I will publish content on various fields that I’m interested in: tech, games, sci-fi, history, languages, music, maps, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is my first post, I’ll begin by talking about the projects I’m currently working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Skwash&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A homegrown issue tracker designed to help you squash bugs&lt;br&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RickyC0626/skwash&quot;&gt;Skwash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a project that I’ve been planning for a while, taking inspiration from existing solutions such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira&quot;&gt;Jira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issues/JT&quot;&gt;YouTrack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab/-/issues&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;. Since an issue tracker is universally recognized by developers and project managers, creating a clone of one or something similar would make its quality easier to judge, and its function easier to understand and showcase. Plus, I get to learn how to plan and build a web app of this scale on my own. Even better, I can use the issue tracker itself to help me build it (recursion!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Second Brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal knowledge management system - long term storage of topics I’ve explored and studied; tip of the iceberg reflection of my brain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around October 2021, I realized that I was forgetting information faster than I can remember. So, I decided to search for a better system that can help retain my knowledge, and also help me make connections between seemingly unrelated ideas. There were many options and apps to choose from, but I opted for &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian.md&lt;/a&gt;, using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortelabs.co/blog/para/&quot;&gt;PARA&lt;/a&gt; method to organize my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vibrainium&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A forum like StackOverflow for you and your future self&lt;br&gt;
— &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RickyC0626/vibrainium&quot;&gt;Vibrainium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project builds upon Skwash and Second Brain, but it is also extremely relevant in the problem solving process for debugging. With forums like StackOverflow, users would ask questions while more experienced users would answer them. In an exchange like this, the users asking questions are disadvantaged, as they are usually not involved in the researching process that would yield them answers. So, instead of waiting for the correct answer to arrive, Vibrainium seeks to encourage users to answer their own questions, either with more specific questions or the final answer they have found. Hopefully, this style of Q&amp;#x26;A between users and themselves could help them become better researchers and logical thinkers.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>